Jalla Subha Chandra

Software Developer

Java Developer with 8.3 years of functional and technical experience in design, development, testing and implementation of Java web applications. I am having proficiency at grasping new technical concepts quickly and utilising same in a productive manner. I am also a good Team player with excellent analytical & communication skills. for a look of my coding skills, please check my GitHub: https://bit.ly/2KHrCsm



1 +91 7975742893

isubhachandra@gmail.com
isubhachandra@gmail.com
isubhachandra@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jallasubhachandra/

KEY SKILLS

Java • Spring • Microservices • Product Development • CICD
• AWS • Agile • SOAP/REST • Backend • Mentoring • Jenkins • Problem Solving

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Quest Global - On-Call Scheduling



June 2019 to Present Bangalore, India

Java developer working with spring in a Micro service architecture running on AWS.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Full stack developer with primary role of application development and team collaboration.
- Involvement in Agile scrum meetings daily stand-ups, backlog refinement, sprint planning and retrospective.
- Active interaction with client for requirement gathering & analysis and upcoming plans.
- Collaboration with offshore and support teams.

Java Developer

Sonata Software



June 2017 to April 2019 Bangalore, India

The main objective in implementing a customer field scheduling solution is to enable customers to schedule specific time slots for service. It will enhance the capabilities to manage field service through online self-service and technical support channels.

Responsibilities

- Develop technical designs for application development.
- Finding new tool and technologies and doing proof of concept for those.
- Introduced i18n Internationalization and theme concepts.

Software Engineer

Capgemini-Innovation



January 2012- May 2017 Bangalore, India

Innovation team, responsible for planning, invent, reinvent and test. I helped to define and build changes to new/existing platforms and deep understanding of customers, cross-category insights and an integration of capabilities. Big thinking and execution at the same table, integrated tools within the same strategic process.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Server Management.
- Writing Backing Beans Classes, Navigation Rules.
- Developed application using spring boot and RESTful API's.

Software Engineer

Teamware Solutions



May 2011 - December 2011 Bangalore, India

Full stack Java EE developer for developing user interface and business logic of a web application for the Aerospace business that allowed predictability of the supply.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Application development using Java.
- Involved in Core product development Server-side coding.
- Troubleshooting client and server-side issues.
- Create RESTful services, business logic (Services) and do CRUD tasks.

TECHNICAL COMPITENCIES

Programming Java 8 & 11, SQL, NodeJS, Python (Scripting), Kotlin, Go, TypeScript

Frameworks Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, Spring Security, Hibernate, JSF, Junit & Mockito

CICD Jenkins, Maven, Sonar, Jacoco, Artifactory

API Swagger, Postman Architectures REST, Microservices

Database MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle, Cassandra

Message Brokers Apache Kafka, Active MQ

Tools IntelliJ, Eclipse, TOAD, SQL Developer, JMeter, SOAP UI

CERTIFICATIONS

Java and Spring Framework, Object Oriented Programming in Java, AWS Concepts, Java Tutorial Course,

Team of The Quarter for Outstanding Contribution.

LANGUAGES

English-fluent, German-elementary

EDUCATION

Master's Degree – Computer Science, Information Technology https://www.skuniversity.org

BSC- Bachelor's Degree https://www.svuniversity.edu.in